MINJOO CHO

Objective & Skills

Objective

I am a polymathic software engineer designing and prototyping ideas for connected experiences with technical toolkits.

I have +10 years of experience working with multidisciplinary design/software teams and have successfully converted innovative ideas into high-fidelity technical prototypes.

I constantly learn and apply new technology to the prototypes to meet the demand for the rapidly evolving landscape of techniques and tools to build intelligence into products.

Focus Areas

Full Stack Development
Fast Prototyping (Internet of Things, Web)
Cloud Platform
User Centred Design

Skills

Software Development

Web - ReactJS, NextJS, TailwindCSS Native - Android API Development - Flask, FastAPI Database - MongoDB, PostgreSQL Cloud - AWS, GCP DevOps - Docker, Git

Hardware Engineering

Embedded - Arduino, micropython Prototyping - RaspberryPi, ESP32/8266 Protocols - MQTT, Websocket, HTTP

Emerging Technology

ML/AI - Langchain, huggingFace AR/VR - Unity, ARCore, Playcanvas

Certificates

AWS Certified Developer Associate Deep Learning Specialisation, Coursera Machine Learning, Coursera

Languages

English (fluent)
Korean (mother tongue)
Japanese (fluent, C2)
Chinese (professional, C1)
German (intermediate, B1)

Work Experience

D-Ford London (Ford Motor Company)¹, Senior Software Engineer

06. 2021 – Present | London, United Kingdom

- Platform engineering: proposed and developed a full-stack IoT prototyping platform for enhanced development experience through automated tools based on microservice architecture
- Technical prototyping: applied technical capabilities into the Human-centred Design process to meet growing demands on tech-driven digital services in Ford's electric vehicles and to deliver new experiences using high-fidelity prototypes

+44 7825 767135 | minjoolisa.cho@gmail.com https://minjoocho.com | github: mj-life-is-once

Related Skills: Platform Engineering · Git · Docker · DevOps · Software Architecture · API Development · Python · ReactJS · Flutter · NoSQL · SQL · Cloud Platform (GCP, AWS) · Usability Testing · User Research · Agile Development · Protopie · Figma · Protopie · Figma · UX Design · hardware prototyping

Indeed Innovation, Creative Technologist

05. 2017 – 04. 2021 | Hamburg, Germany

- Client consultation: project pitch, co-creation workshop, project progress report
- Technical prototyping: developed high-fidelity PoC prototypes to solve design problems spanning various industrial sectors. (Aerospace, home appliances etc.)
- Marketing event support: End-to-end implementation and demonstration of interactive installations that converted emerging technology intro meaning user interactions

Related Skills: Fast-prototyping · Emerging technology · Technical consulting · Client management · Cloud Platform (GCP, AWS) · UX Engineering · Arduino · RaspberryPi

Samsung Creative Lab², Creative Strategist & Developer

06. 2013 - 10. 2014 | Suwon, South Korea

- Product strategy: product concept development, stakeholder management
- Prototype development: developed multi-modal prototype (hardware with haptic feedback, android application development for music visualisation)
- User research: planned and conducted user research in collaboration with the Korean Deaf Society
- Regular project progress report to C-level representatives

Samsung Electronics, Product Manager

01. 2011 – 12. 2014 | Suwon, South Korea

- Projects: Samsung Galaxy Tablet 10 Series, Google Nexus 10 (A joint-project with Google)
- Product Lifecycle Management: solved procedural issues during the entire product life cycle from the development stage to the end of production
- Regular project progress report to C-level representatives

Education

KAIST, MSc in Industrial Design

08. 2015 - 07. 2017 | Daejeon, South Korea

- Full scholarship
- Master's thesis: Calm Automaton, A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays

KAIST, BSc in Electrical Engineering

02. 2006 - 01. 2011 | Daejeon, South Korea

Full scholarship

¹ D-Ford is an R&D lab focused on developing services, products, and visions for the future of mobility based on the human-centred design (HCD) approach.

² Samsung Creative Lab is Samsung incubation program for Samsung employees to incubate creative ideas into real projects